Guide to the Walter Prichard Eaton Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Walter Prichard Eaton writings
1919-1954
YCAL MSS 505
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.84
(2 boxes)
The writings consist of manuscript and typescript drafts of various works by Walter Prichard Eaton. Included is a typescript draft of The Ecole Des Beaux-Arts in the 90's by Charles Morris.
Eaton, Walter Prichard, 1878-1957
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Walter Prichard Eaton, 1878–1957
Walter Prichard Eaton, American drama critic and author. He was Associate Professor of Playwriting at Yale University.
Scope and Contents
The writings consist of manuscript and typescript drafts of various works by Walter Prichard Eaton. Included is a typescript draft of "The Ecole Des Beaux-Arts in the 90's" by Charles Morris.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Drama -- 20th Century; Drama criticism -- United States; Theater critics -- United States; Theater critics -- United States; Eaton, Walter Prichard, 1878-1957; Morris, Charles, 1869-1930; Yale University -- Faculty
- Writings, 1919-1954, undated; Series I; 0.84; (2 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Writings by Eaton
    - "About Boys' Books," manuscript draft, 1924 (Box 1)
    - "All the World's a Stage," manuscript draft, undated (Box 1)
    - "The Almost Invisible Garden," manuscript draft with watercolor illustrations, undated (Box 1)
    - "American Drama," manuscript draft, undated (Box 1)
    - "The American Theatre Today," manuscript and typescript drafts, undated (Box 1)
    - "American Wing of the Metropolitan," manuscript draft, undated (Box 1)
    - "Anthracite Versus Oil," typescript draft, undated (Box 1)
    - "Are you a Joiner," typescript draft, undated (Box 1)
    - "The Art of the Playwright," typescript draft, undated (Box 1)
    - "The Baby," typescript draft with photographs, undated (Box 1)
    - "Berkshire History," typescript draft, undated (Box 1)
    - "The Better Things of Life: The Theatre," manuscript draft, undated (Box 1)
    - "The Boy and the Book," typescript draft, undated (Box 1)
    - "Chapel Hill Talk," typescript draft, 1950 (Box 1)
    - "The Choice of Earth," typescript draft, undated (Box 1)
    - "Conservation," manuscript and typescript draft, 1935 (Box 1)
    - "Crime in Vermont," typescript draft, 1939 (Box 1)
    - "A Critic's Memories," manuscript draft, undated (Box 1)
    - "David Garrick," typescript draft, undated (Box 1)
    - "Dunbart Birdsall: A Hit and Two Misses," typescript draft with illustrations, undated (Box 1)
    - "Elevating the Stage," proofs, undated (Box 1)
    - Essays, various untitled, manuscript drafts, undated (Box 2)
    - "Essays of Our Own Elia," typescript draft, 1919 (Box 2)
    - "Footnote to Murder," typescript draft, 1954 (Box 2)
    - "Fundamentalism Reaches the Stage," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "Grandma- Old Style," typescript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "The Great Road," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "The Hated Spot," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "Her Name was Normal," manuscript and typescript drafts, undated (Box 2)
    - "How's Your Lawn?" manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "The Joy of Tools," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "Listerns' Theatre," typescript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "Modern Mystery," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "Notes on Our Slang Drama," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "The Nutcracker," typescript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "Period House," typescript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "Play Writing," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - Poems, various untitled, manuscript and typescript drafts, undated (Box 2)
    - "The Purple Door Knob," manuscript and typescript drafts, undated (Box 2)
    - [Shaw], manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "Spring Again," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "Sweets for Squirrels," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "The Theatre and the Colleged," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "To The Dogs," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "What Can You Do With Your Hands?" manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "When We Had Antiques and Didn't Know It," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - [Winter], manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
    - "You Can't Stump Me," manuscript draft, undated (Box 2)
  - Writings by Others
    - Morris, Charles. "The Ecole Des Beaux-Arts in the 90's," typescript draft, undated (Box 2)